Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin autograph collection, 1833-2008.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen autograph collection
- Gandhi, Indira Addressee: Mr. Paul Dennett Writer's location: New Delhi, March 31, 1975; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Her definition as to what politics means.
  Rudin # A-88
- Gandhi, Indira Addressee: Mr. John Simmons Writer's location: New Delhi, April 10, 1980; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Philosophically comments on life and history.
  Rudin # A-89
- Gandhi, Mohandas Writer's location: Bombay Congress Bulletin, January 23, 1931; Mimeographed Page Signed8.25" x 13"; Pages: 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Inflammatory newsletter promoting Indian independence.
  Rudin # A-90
- Garrison, William Lloyd Addressee: Wm H. Sweetser Writer's location: Boston, June 25, 1852; ALS - 7" x 7.75"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  What ever may be the color of his skin, "a man's a man for a' that".
  Rudin # A-91
- Garrison, William Lloyd Addressee: Doctor Church Writer's location: Boston, September 18, 1855; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 4 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Garrison helps organize anti-slavery lectures and names leading figures of the day in the abolitionist movement.
  Rudin # A-92
- Gatling, R.J. Addressee: Mr. Welles Writer's location: Hartford, CT, February 4, 1879; ALS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Gatling suggests using the improved Gatling Gun to protect the Treasury Building in Washington, D.C.
  Rudin # A-93
- George III Addressee: Richard Rigby, Paymaster General Writer's location: Court at St. James's, April 16, 1776; DS Small Legal Folio; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  The King directs payment to General Sir Jeffrey Amherst.
  Rudin # A-94
- George V Addressee: "My dear Baron" Writer's location: Sandringham, Norfolk, December 17, 1895; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Thank you note the birth of his son, George IV.
  Rudin # A-95
- Gershwin, George Addressee: "Dear Walter" Writer's location: n.p., August 26, 1926; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Letter discussing his satisfaction with "Tip Toes" and his work on "Oh Kay!"
  Rudin # A-96
- Getty, Jean Paul Addressee: "Dear parents" Writer's location: Hamburg, Germany, July 6, 1913; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 6 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Lengthy letter to his parents about his travel, his finances and his disgust that his parents don't write to him more "oftener".
  Rudin # A-97
- Getty, Jean Paul Addressee: To his father Writer's location: Vienna, Austria, Early November 1913; ALS 8" x 13"; Pages: 12 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  Writes his father about his father's poor business-making decisions. He fails to understand his father's attitude towards him as he approaches his twenty first birthday.
  Rudin # A-98
- Getty, Jean Paul Addressee: "Dear father and mother" Writer's location: Pall Mall, London, July 18, 1920; ALS 5" x 7"; Pages: 4 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Getty discusses business and the fact that money is so visible - comments on the many Rolls Royce's he sees.
  Rudin # A-99
- Getty, Jean Paul Addressee: "Dearest father" Writer's location: Pall Mall, London, July 20, 1920; ALS 5" x 7"; Pages: 4 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Discusses production of oil wells, financial conditions in London and his contacts.
  Rudin # A-100
- Getty, Jean Paul Addressee: Gerald M. Loeb Writer's location: Guilford, Surrey, March 15, 1965; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  "I have never considered myself a business man but rather a man who is interested in many things, including business".
  Rudin # A-101
- Getty, Jean Paul Addressee: Gerald M. Loeb Writer's location: Guilford, Surrey, December 17, 1970, January 8, 14, 21, 1971; TLS 4to & 8vo; Pages: 4 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Four letter correspondence regarding the book "Battle for Stock Market Profits".
  Rudin # A-102
- Goldman, Emma Addressee: Mr. Elsbach, July 30, 1916; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Goldman writes on the subject of voting.
  Rudin # A-103
- Gore, Al, December 13, 2000; Typed Statement Signed - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Al Gore's Concession Speech - Presidential Election - 2000.
  Rudin # A-104
- Greatbatch, Wilson - the inventor of the Pacemaker Writer's location: n.p., January 17, 1995; Drawing Signed 6.75" x 10 .25"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  The inventor of the pacemaker draws a diagram of the inner workings of a heart pacemaker.
  Rudin # A-105
- Greeley, Horace Addressee: A.M. Ide, Jr. Writer's location: New York, December 11, 1844; ALS - 10" x 7.75"; Pages: 1 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Offers a word of counsel about writing.
  Rudin # A-106
- Greeley, Horace Addressee: John D. Baldwin Writer's location: New York, August 15, 1846; ALS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  Greeley shows his determination to do what is right regardless of consequences.
  Rudin # A-107
- Greeley, Horace Addressee: "Dear Sir" Writer's location: Office of the Tribune New York, July 1, 1863; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 3 1/2 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  He advises an Englishman to "Go West".
  Rudin # A-108
- Greeley, Horace Addressee: Mr. O.D. Case Writer's location: Office of the Tribune New York, June 26, 1864; ALS 5.25" x 8"; Pages: 3 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  Complains of delays in the production of the first volume of his book on the Civil War, "The American Conflict".
  Rudin # A-109
- Hamilton, Alexander Addressee: The President and Directors of the Bank of the United States Writer's location: Philadelphia, March 26, 1793; LS 4to; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Hamilton requests a loan of $800,000 to enable the government to operate for the year 1793.
  Rudin # A-110
- Hammerstein, Oscar Addressee: R.A. Wachsman Writer's location: Doylestown, PA, January 19, 1941; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Doesn't recollect "Make Believe" ever being considered a river song.
  Rudin # A-111
- Hearst, William Randolph Addressee: Mr. Norcross, ALS; Pages: 4 (Box 4, Folder 1A)
  Hearst gives instructions to an editor for a forthcoming magazine issue
  Rudin # A-112
- Hancock, John, November 30,1776; DS; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 1B)
  Hancock, as President of the Continental Congress, assigns a Captain to a company in the Army.
- Henry, Patrick, February 27, 1797; ADS - 6.25" x 7.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Takes responsibility for any financial obligations assumed by his friend, Philip Payne.
  Rudin # A-113
- Herzl, Theodore, March 16, 1903; ALS 5.25" x 9"; Pages: 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Discusses a new play about to open in Berlin. (In German with translation).
  Rudin # A-114
- Hirschfeld, Al Addressee: Mr. and Mrs. William Post, Jr. Writer's location: New York, NY, July 19, 1942; TLS- 3.5" x 6.5"; Pages: 1, with envelope (Box 4, Folder 1C)
  Letter of thanks to good friends with amusing sketch on envelope and self portrait on letter.
  Rudin # A-115
- Hirschfeld, Al Addressee: Barry Lindeman Writer's location: New York, NY, December 27, 1988; TLS - 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Response to an admirer looking for a freebie.
  Rudin # A-116
- Hirschfeld, Al, August 27, 1993; Card-3 x 5; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 2a)
  Original signed ink self-portrait. With First Day of Issue postage stamps designed by Hirschfeld, of comedians and silent screen stars.
  Rudin # A-117
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell Addressee: Vaughan Writer's location: Boston, October 17, 1902; ALS 8" x 5"; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Writes about his upcoming appointment to the U.S. Supreme Court.
  Rudin # A-118
- Howe, Julia Ward Writer's location: New York London, February 1862; Printed Magazine 6.5" x 9.75"; Pages: 134 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  First printing of "The Battle Hymn of the Republic" in The Atlantic Monthly.
  Rudin # A-119
- Howe, Julia Ward Addressee: Mrs. L. Imman Writer's location: Newport, RI, September 30, 1882; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 3 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  She has read with great pleasure of a Women's Suffrage Society being formed.
  Rudin # A-120
- Humphrey, Hubert H. Addressee: Chester Kerr, Director of Yale University Press Writer's location: Washington, D.C., September 25, 1968; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  His thoughts on the management of the Democratic Convention in Chicago.
  Rudin # A-121
- Kallir, Otto Addressee: Louis Caldor Writer's location: New York, 1940-1945; TLS - 4to; Pages: 17 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Archive of art dealings with Grandma Moses and her agent Louis Caldor. See also Grandma Moses.
  Rudin # A-122
- Kaufman, George S. Addressee: Edna Ferber Writer's location: New York City, Early 1950's Thursday; TLS & Article Typed 7" x 8.5" - Ltr 4to - Article; Pages: 1 6 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Six page transcript of an article he was writing about Ferber for Cosmopolitan. Also with a cover letter to Ferber.
  Rudin # A-123
- Kaufman, George S. Addressee: Edna Ferber Writer's location: Holicong, PA, Friday; ALS 7.25" x 10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Speaks of joint plans for collaboration.
  Rudin # A-124
- Keller, Helen, March 17, 1905; Signed Photo 6.75" x 8.25" (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Signed photograph in her graduation robe.
  Rudin # A-125
- Keller, Helen Addressee: Edwin Elsbach Writer's location: Wrentham, Mass., June 13, 1917; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 1/2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Writes her feelings about soldiers who have lost their sight during the war.
  Rudin # A-126
- Keller, Helen Addressee: Elmer V. Griggs Writer's location: Forest Hills, NY, November 24, 1936; TLS - 7.25" x 10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 11a)
  Keller writes a heartfelt remembrance on the influence of Anne Sullivan in her life. This letter is also a statement of thanks to a generous contributor to the American Foundation for the Blind.
  Rudin # A-126A
- Kennedy, Jacqueline Addressee: Mrs. Moody Writer's location: New York, January 6, 1973; ALS 5.25" x 7.5"; Pages: 3 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Writes to Caroline's school about the relationship and effect of the Secret Service on her daughter Caroline.
  Rudin # A-127
- Kennedy, Jacqueline Addressee: Eleanor Beard Writer's location: Hardinsburg, KY, January 6, 1958; ALS; Pages: 3 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Orders slipper tips with accompanying swatches of blue velvet and receipts.
  Rudin # A-128
- King, Jr. Martin Luther Addressee: Jacob Bacal Writer's location: Atlanta, Georgia, January 4, 1962; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Thanks a supporter "convinced that we stand on the threshold of our nation's bright tomorrow". Also includes commemorative stamps and envelopes.
  Rudin # A-130
- Kinsey, Alfred C. Addressee: Peter Briggs Writer's location: Bloomington, Indiana, March 10, 1952; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Relationship between male sex hormones and cancer.
  Rudin # A-131
- Lake, Simon
  See the Gail and Stephen Rudin Simon Lake Collection #6992
- Lee, Robert E.
  See the Gail and Stephen Rudin Civil War Collection,#4696, Rudin # A-139
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Ray Fernstrom Writer's location: New York City, June 21, 1929; TLS-4to; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Lindbergh looks forward to a time when transatlantic aviation is a relatively safe commercial enterprise.
  Rudin # A-140
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: "Dear Anne" (His Wife) Writer's location: Washington, DC, April 21, 1939; ALS 6" x 8"; Pages: 3 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Lindbergh writes his wife after returning from Europe amid negative press for his views on World War II. Takes pains to shield his children from publicity.
  Rudin # A-141
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Disuked (Philippines), July 25, 1970; AMsS 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 6 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Lindberg writes of his wildlife conservation efforts in the Philippines and his regard for the establishment of the Private Association for National Minorities.
  Rudin # A-142
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Vaud, Switzerland, August 1, 1973; DS 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  On book royalties, Freemasonry, and fund raising.
  Rudin # A-143
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Detroit, MI, February 4, 1902; Envelope 4" x 7.5" (Box 4, Folder 20)
  "Charles Lindbergh" Cover - 22 Kt. Gold Stamp replica.
  Rudin # A-144
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Mr. Joseph Klingler Writer's location: St. Louis, MO, February 20, 1928; Envelope 3.75" x 6.5" (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Air mail envelope "Lindbergh Again Flies The Air Mail".
  Rudin # A-145
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Clyde Kelly Writer's location: n.p., February 18, 1929; TLS - 6.25" x 7; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Letter arguing for extending air mail service to the countries of Central America.
  Rudin # A-145A
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Mr. L. B. Gatchell Writer's location: Cristobal to Miami, May 1, 1930; Envelope 3.5" x 6.5" (Box 4, Folder 23)
  First non-stop regular Air Mail flight Cristobal to Miami by Lindbergh.
  Rudin # A-146
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Bill Schneider Jr. Writer's location: Cienfuegos to Jamaica, November 19, 1931; Envelope 3.5" x 6.5" (Box 4, Folder 24)
  First flight Cienfuegos to Jamaica by Lindbergh.
  Rudin # A-147
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Chicago, Illinois, May 28, 1998; Envelope 3.5" x 6.5" (Box 4, Folder 25)
  First Solo Transatlantic Flight-1927 / First Day of Issue stamp and cover.
  Rudin # A-148
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Edward J. Meehan Writer's location: Havana, Cuba, February 8, 1928; Envelope 3.5" x 6.5" (Box 4, Folder 26)
  1828 Cuba Lindbergh Air Mail First Day Cover.
  Rudin # A-148A
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Mr. Christopher, Chairman of Contest Committee Writer's location: Roosevelt Field, Long Island NY, April 20, 1930; DOC S 8.5" x 13"; Pages: 1 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  A signed time certification for the arrival of Lindbergh and his wife at Roosevelt Field, Long Island, NY - Setting a transcontinental speed record from Los Angeles to Roosevelt Field.
  Rudin # A-149
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: W.R. Ware Writer's location: Chicago - St. Louis, April 15, 1926; Envelope 3.5" x 6.5" (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Postal cover flown Air Mail on the first flight from Chicago to St. Louis.
  Rudin # A-150
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Illinois, April 1926; Photo 5.25" x 6.75" (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Photo showing Lindbergh loading air mail for first Illinois CAM flight #2.
  Rudin # A-151
- Lindbergh, Charles, 1927; Photo 4.5" x 6.5" (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Lindbergh flying his plane to Roosevelt Field for takeoff on his transatlantic flight.
  Rudin # A-152
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Nashville, May 20, 1927; Newspaper 17.5" x 23.75"; Pages: 28 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Nashville Banner headline "Lindbergh Takes Off For Paris".
  Rudin # A-153
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: New York, May 22, 1927; Newspaper 18" x 22.5" (Box 10, Folder 4)
  New York Times headline "Lindbergh Does It!".
  Rudin # A-154
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: New York, May 23, 1927; Newspaper 18.25" x 22.25" (Box 10, Folder 5)
  New York Times headline "Lindbergh's Own Story of Epochal Flight...".
  Rudin # A-155
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Albany, NY, June 14, 1927; Newspaper 17" x 21" (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Knickerbocker Press headline "Millions in Lindbergh Spectacle".
  Rudin # A-155A
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: n.p., 1927; Printed Poster Signed 19" x 26.5"; Pages: 1 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  Signed Spirit of St. Louis Poster.
  Rudin # A-156
- Lindbergh, Charles Addressee: Mr. Everett Cassagneres Writer's location: Darien, CT, April 7, 1968; TLS - Quarto; Pages: 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Lindbergh debunks the myth about the title of his book, "We", discusses the design of the "Spirit of St. Louis", and tells an amusing story about a flight over the Grand Canyon.
  Rudin # A-156A
- Lindbergh, Charles Writer's location: Garden City, NY, May 20, 2002; Ptd Folio 8.5" x 10.25"; Pages: 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Charles Lindbergh's Solo Transatlantic Flight - 75th Anniversary Folio.
  Rudin # A-157
- Livermore, Mary Addressee: Mrs. Cole Writer's location: Melrose, May 8, 1905; ALS Large 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  She is pleased to present a gift on behalf of the American Woman Suffrage Association to Henry Blackwell.
  Rudin # A-158
- Lodge, Henry Cabot Addressee: E.E. Gaylord, Esq. Writer's location: United States Senate, October 15, 1918; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Lodge discusses German surrender terms.
  Rudin # A-159
- Lodge, Henry Cabot Addressee: Charles G. Washburn Writer's location: United States Senate, January 1, 1919; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Lodge's opinions on Wilson's thoughts and actions in regard to future wars.
  Rudin # A-160
- MacArthur, Douglas Addressee: To The People Of The Philippines Writer's location: General Headquarters Southwest Pacific Area, n.d.; Printed DOC 7.5" x 10"; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Printed Proclamation - "I have returned".
  Rudin # A-161
- MacArthur, Douglas Addressee: Charles l. Dean National Commander - National Society - Army of the Philippines Writer's location: General Headquarter Southwest Pacific Area, July 13, 1944; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Douglas McArthur promises Philippine veterans to raise their flag over Corregidor. (With supporting letter from Commander Dean).
  Rudin # A-162
- Malcolm X Writer's location: n.p., n.d.; Typed DOCS 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Malcolm X proofreads and approves a portion of his 1964 interview conducted by Alex Hailey.
  Rudin # A-163
- Marconi, Guglielmo Addressee: T.C. Martini Writer's location: South Wellfleet, MA, January 21, 1903; ALS Large 8vo; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Marconi mentions the wireless transmission made by Teddy Roosevelt to King Edward VII.
  Rudin # A-164
- Marshall, George C. Addressee: Dr. Watson Wharton Writer's location: Pinehurst, NC, December 23, 1947; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Marshall on military disciplines.
  Rudin # A-165
- Marshall, John Addressee: William B. Sprague Writer's location: Richmond, VA, March 23, 1833; ALS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Marshall comments on the evils of alcohol and praises the effort of the early temperance movements in the U.S.
  Rudin # A-166
- Meir, Golda Addressee: Theodore Cohn Writer's location: n.p., December 22, 1969; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  The solidarity of the Jewish people will overcome its obstacles.
  Rudin # A-167
- Mitchell, William Lendrum "Billy" Addressee: Robert J. Braly Writer's location: Middleburg, VA, January 26, 1929; TLS 6.5" x 10.25"; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Writes about the future of air travel.
  Rudin # A-168
- Morse, Samuel F.B. Addressee: Lt. Col. John R. Leslie Writer's location: New York, May, 1862; ALS - 3.375" x 5.875"; Pages: 1 (Box 5, Folder 17a)
  Morse explains the true meaning of an autograph
  Rudin # A-169
- Morse, Samuel F.B. Addressee: Lt. Col. John R. Leslie Writer's location: New York, March 4, 1870; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  "A little instrument...constructed for...using ...embossed paper for automatic transmission of dispatches".
  Rudin # A-170
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Louis Caldor Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, November 27, unknown year; ALS 4.75" x 7.25"; Pages: 4 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Discusses Caldor's separation from his wife - Moses also mentions her art.
  Rudin # A-171
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Louis Caldor Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, June 27, 1938; ALS 5" x 7.75"; Pages: 2 1/2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Grandma Moses writes about her methods, limitations and her materials.
  Rudin # A-172
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Louis Caldor Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, July 29, 1938; ALS 5" x 7.75"; Pages: 4 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  "I will not paint for anyone else...It is strange what some people like...".
  Rudin # A-173
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Louis Caldor Writer's location: Postmarked Hoosick Falls, NY, May 16, 1939; ALS 5.25" x 6.5"; Pages: 2 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  Grandma Moses wants to sell some of her pictures into the Albany Institute of Art and "strike while the iron is hot".
  Rudin # A-174
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Mrs. Robert Kent ("My Dear Girl Hazle") Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, November 26, 1940; ALS 8" x 10"; Pages: 3 1/2 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Writes of her increasing popularity, her visit to NY and her mortality.
  Rudin # A-175
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Louis Caldor Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, April 1, 1941; ALS 5.25" x 6.5"; Pages: 2 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  "I'm not sending any paintings to the Albany exhibit as there is not anything in it for me." Also says she has to put aside painting so she can care for some children.
  Rudin # A-176
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Mr. Caldor Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, January 26, 1942; ALS 5" x 6.5"; Pages: 3 (Box 5, Folder 23a)
  Moses writes Caldor about her boys preparing for the war and about her painting.
  Rudin # A-177
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Louis Caldor Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, July 3, 1943; ALS 8" x 10"; Pages: 4 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Mentions a photograph that makes her look "as fierce as a goose with one eye". Talks about all her sales and how busy she is. Tells Caldor "you are the one that set the ball a rolling". Says "I'm asking much more for the paintings" because all her materials cost more.
  Rudin # A-178
- Grandma Moses Addressee: Mrs. Georgie Adams Writer's location: Eagle Bridge, NY, August 23, 1946; ALS 5.5" x 7"; Pages: 2 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Grandma Moses offers advice to an aspiring artist, "You can never tell what you can do till you try".
  Rudin # A-179
- Grandma Moses Writer's location: Harper & Brothers Publishers New York, 1946; Signed Book; Pages: 140
  Half red leather book entitled, "My Life's History". No. 250 of 250. See Separate Material below.
  Rudin # A-180
- Nation, Carry A. Addressee: "Brother" Writer's location: Fox Vaudeville Booking Exchange, November 12 unknown year; ALS 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  I was arrested here...someone paid the fine $10...wanted to ask you about bringing a suit before the Supreme Court".
  Rudin # A-181
- Nelson, Lord Horatio Addressee: The Respective Captains, or Commanders of any of His Majesty's Ships... Writer's location: Nelson's ship "The Victory" off Toulon, December 4, 1803; Ms Doc S Legal Folio; Pages: 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Directs the fleet's captains to put themselves under his Command.
  Rudin # A-182
- Nightingale, Florence Addressee: Elizabeth Gaskell Writer's location: London, October 3, 1860; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 6 1/2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Nightingale seeks help in establishing a "Soldier's Home" at Gibraltar.
  Rudin # A-183
- Nightingale, Florence Addressee: Hon. Miss. Campbell Writer's location: London, April 6, 1868; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 7 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Nightingale writes of the problems of filing nursing positions. With book "Florence Nightingale" by Cecil Wordham Smith - Constable, London - 1950.
  Rudin # A-184
- Nightingale, Florence Addressee: Mr. Needham Writer's location: n.p., October 29, 1881; LS - 4.5" x 7"; Pages: 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Nightingale paves the road for another nursing school.
  Rudin # A-185
- O'Keefe Georgia Addressee: James Thrall Soby ? Writer's location: Albuquerque, NM, May 27, 1954; ALS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Writes of a performance involving bulls that she saw and of an aspiring artist, Arthur Dove.
  Rudin # A-186
- Parrish, Maxfield Addressee: Frank Chouteau Brown Writer's location: Windsor, Vermont, June 18, 1901; ALS 8" x 10"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Beautifully-penned letter sending a page of lettering.
  Rudin # A-187
- Pershing, John J. Addressee: Colonel W.C. Church Writer's location: Fort Bliss, Texas, August 18, 1914; TLS 8" x 5"; Pages: 1 1/2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Pershing urges U.S. preparedness just after World War I has broken out.
  Rudin # A-188
- Pershing, John J. Addressee: Major General William H. Carter Writer's location: In the Field, Mexico, January 9, 1917; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 6, Folder 8)